Oliver Otis Howard Papers M091 M091
George J. Mitchell Department of Special Collections & Archives, Bowdoin College Library, Brunswick, Maine 04011
Oliver Otis Howard papers
Bulk, 1846-1908
1833-1912, undated
M091
George J. Mitchell Department of Special Collections & Archives, Bowdoin College Library, Brunswick, Maine 04011
60.0 linear feet
Correspondence, articles, addresses, lectures, publications, diaries, clippings, indexes, photographs, and other material from the personal and unofficial professional records of Oliver Otis Howard.
Howard, O.O., (Oliver Otis), 1830-1909
Agency History / Biographical Note
Oliver Otis Howard (1830-1909, Bowdoin 1850), a career officer in the United States Army, rose to the rank of bvt. maj. general in the volunteers and, later, in the regular army. During the Civil War, he fought at Bull Run, Fair Oaks, Fredericksburg, Chancellorsville, Gettysburg, Chattanooga, and in Sherman's march through Georgia. After the Civil War, Howard was appointed commissioner of the Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands (1865-1873). Subsequent appointments included: commander of the Department of the Columbia (1874-1880) during the Nez Perce War; superintendent of the United States Military Academy at West Point (1880-1882); commander of the Department of the Platte (1882-1886) and the Divisions of the Pacific (1886-1888) and the East (1888-1894).
Howard was instrumental in founding Howard University and Lincoln Memorial University. Howard was graduated from Bowdoin College in 1850 and from West Point in 1854. He served at Watervliet Arsenal in West Troy, New York (1854-1855); Kennebec Arsenal in Augusta, Maine (1855-1856); and in the Seminole Wars in Florida (1856-1857).
In 1872, he led a peace mission to Cochise. Howard was also involved in Republican Party politics, the Congregational Home Missionary Society, the Young Men's Christian Association, the Military Order of the Loyal Legion, and the Congregational Church.
Howard was the author of several works, including The Autobiography of Oliver Otis Howard (1907), My Life and Experiences Among our Hostile Indians (1907) and Famous Indian Chiefs I Have Known (1908). In 1855, Howard married Elizabeth "Lizzie" Ann Waite (1832-1911) of Portland, Maine. The couple had seven children: Guy Howard (1855-1899); Grace Ellen Howard Gray (1856-1949); James "Jamie" Waite Howard (1860-1932); Chancey Otis Howard (1863-1934); John Howard (b. 1867); Harry Stinson Howard (1869-1960); and Elizabeth "Bessie" Howard Bancroft (1871-1941).
Scope and Content
Correspondence, articles, addresses, lectures, publications, diaries, clippings, indexes and other material from the personal and unofficial professional records of Oliver Otis Howard. Also includes images from a variety of sources. Howard corresponded with more than 14,000 people, including notables in the military, social reformation, politics and law, religion, education, literature and journalism, and the arts.
Correspondents include: Henry Ward Beecher, Blanche K. Bruce, Andrew Carnegie, Salmon P. Chase, George Crook, Dorothea Dix, Frederick Douglass, James A. Garfield, William Lloyd Garrison, Ulysses S. Grant, Edward Everett Hale, Winfield S. Hancock, Rutherford B. Hayes, William Randolph Hearst, Sarah Winnemucca Hopkins, William McKinley, Montgomery C. Meigs, Nelson A. Miles, Dwight L. Moody, Theodore Roosevelt, Elihu Root, Carl Schurz, Philip H. Sheridan, John Sherman, William T. Sherman, Daniel E. Sickles, Edwin M. Stanton, Charles Sumner, William H. Taft, Soujourner Truth and Booker T. Washington.
His most voluminous correspondence (minimum of 110 letters received each) was with: Charles F. Eager of Lincoln Memorial University; Cyrus Kehr, speaking agent; John Hale Larry of Lincoln Memorial University; Henry F. McCoy of the San Francisco Y.M.C.A.; J. E. Rankin of Howard University; Wager Swayne of the Freedmen's Bureau in Alabama; and Eliphalet Whittlesey of the Board of Indian Commissioners.
The collections of Howard's brothers, Charles Henry Howard and Rowland Bailey Howard supplement this material.
Reproduction Note
- M91.1: Correspondence, early life, 1833-May 1861, M91.1; 1.5 linear feet
  Series Description:
  This correspondence is largely composed of family letters from Howard's youth and early military career. Included are the years he spent as a student at North Yarmouth Academy, Bowdoin College (Class of 1850) and USMA (Class of 1854); as well as his military service in Florida's Seminole Wars (1856-57) and as instructor of mathematics at USMA (1857-61).
  Arrangement:
  Arranged chronologically.
  Reproduction Note:
  This series is available online.
  - 1833 Jul 14 - 1843 Nov 06 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1844 Jan 11 - 1844 Nov 24 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1845 Jan 19 - 1845 Dec 28 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1846 Jan 18 - 1846 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1846 Jun 02 - 1846 Nov 29 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1847 Jan 01 - 1847 Apr 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1847 Jun 15 - 1847 Dec 23 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1848 Jan 01 - 1848 Jul 30 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1848 Aug 16 - 1848 Dec 13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1849 Jan 14 - 1849 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1849 Jun 02 - 1849 Dec 22 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1850 Jan (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1850 Feb (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1850 Mar (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1850 Apr (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1850 Jun (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1850 Jul (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1850 Aug (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1850 Sep (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1850 Oct (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1850 Nov (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1850 Dec (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1851 Jan (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1851 Feb (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1851 Mar (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1851 Apr (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1851 May (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1851 Jun (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 1851 Jul (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1851 Aug (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 1851 Sep (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 1851 Oct (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 1851 Nov (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 1851 Dec (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 1852 Jan (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - 1852 Feb (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 1852 Mar (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 1852 Apr (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 1852 May (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 1852 Jun (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 1852 Jul (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - 1852 Aug (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - 1852 Sep (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - 1852 Oct (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - 1852 Nov (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - 1852 Dec (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - 1853 Jan (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - 1853 Feb (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - 1853 Mar (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - 1853 Apr (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - 1853 May (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - 1853 June (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - 1853 Jul (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - 1853 Aug (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - 1853 Sep (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - 1853 Oct (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - 1853 Nov (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - 1853 Dec (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - 1854 Jan (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - 1854 Feb (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - 1854 Mar (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - 1854 Apr (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - 1854 May (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - 1854 Jun (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - 1854 Sep (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - 1854 Oct (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - 1854 Nov (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - 1855 Jan (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - 1855 Feb (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - 1855 May (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - 1855 Jun (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - 1855 Aug (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - 1855 Sep (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - 1855 Oct (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - 1855 Nov (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - 1855 Dec (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - 1856 Jan (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - 1856 Feb (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - 1856 Mar (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - 1856 Apr (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - 1856 May (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - 1856 Jun (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - 1856 Jul (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - 1856 Aug (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - 1856 Sep (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - 1856 Oct (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - 1856 Nov (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - 1856 Dec (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - 1857 Jan (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - 1857 Feb (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - 1857 Mar (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - 1857 Apr (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - 1857 May (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - 1857 Jun (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - 1857 Jul (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - 1857 Aug (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - 1857 Sep (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - 1857 Oct (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - 1857 Nov (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - 1857 Dec (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - 1858 Jan (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - 1858 Feb (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - 1858 Mar (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - 1858 Apr (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - 1858 May (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - 1858 Jun (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - 1858 Jul (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - 1858 Aug (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - 1858 Sep (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - 1858 Oct (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - 1858 Nov (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - 1858 Dec (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - 1859 Jan (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - 1859 Feb (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - 1859 Mar (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - 1859 Apr (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - 1859 May (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1859 Jun (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1859 Jul (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1859 Aug (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1859 Sep (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1859 Oct (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1859 Nov (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1859 Dec (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1860 Jan (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1860 Feb (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1860 Mar (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1860 Apr (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1860 May (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1860 Jun (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1860 Jul (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1860 Aug (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1860 Sep (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1860 Oct (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1860 Nov (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1860 Dec (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1861 Jan (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1861 Feb (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1861 Mar (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 1861 Apr (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 1861 May (Box 2, Folder 25)
- M91.2: Correspondence, Civil War, June 1861-April 1865, M91.2; 1.25 linear feet
  Civil War era correspondence with family and friends; also includes letters from other military officers. Letterpress copies (M91.7) of correspondence sent by Howard starting in 1864 are also available. Covered is his service with the 3rd Maine regiment (Jun-Sep 1861), and the 2nd corps (Sep 1861-Jun 1862); in command of the 2nd division (Aug 1862-Mar 1863), the 11th corps (Mar 1863-Apr 1864), the 4th corps (Apr-Jul 1864) and the Army of the Tennessee (Jul 1864-Apr 1865). Battles and campaigns include Fair Oaks, First and Second Manassas, Gettysburg, Chancellorsville and the Atlanta Campaign.
  - 1861 Jun (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 1861 Jul (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 1861 Aug 01 - 1861 Aug 15 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 1861 Aug 16 - 1861 Aug 31 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 1861 Sep 01 - 1861 Sep 15 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 1861 Sep 16 - 1861 Sep 30 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 1861 Oct 01 - 1861 Oct 09 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 1861 Oct 10 - 1861 Oct 19 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 1861 Oct 20 - 1861 Oct 31 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 1861 Nov (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 1861 Dec (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 1862 Jan (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 1862 Feb (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 1862 Mar (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - 1862 Apr (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 1862 May (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - 1862 Jun 02 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - 1862 Jun 05 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - 1862 Jun (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - 1862 Jul (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - 1862 Aug (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 1862 Sep (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - 1862 Oct (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - 1862 Nov (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - 1862 Dec (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - 1863 Jan (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - 1863 Feb (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - 1863 Mar (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - 1863 Apr (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - 1863 May (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - 1863 Jun (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - 1863 Jul (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - 1863 Aug (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - 1863 Sep (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - 1863 Oct (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - 1863 Nov (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - 1863 Dec (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - 1864 Jan (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - 1864 Feb (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - 1864 Mar (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - 1864 Apr 01 - 1864 Apr 11 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - 1864 Apr 12 - 1864 Apr 30 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - 1864 May (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - 1864 Jun (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - 1864 Jul (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - 1864 Aug (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - 1864 Sep 01 - 1864 Sep 20 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - 1864 Sep 21 - 1864 Sep 30 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - 1864 Oct (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1864 Nov (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1864 Dec (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1865 Jan (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1865 Feb (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1865 Mar (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1865 Apr 01 - 1865 Apr 14 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1865 Apr 15 - 1865 Apr 30 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- M91.3: Correspondence, Freedmen's Bureau period, May 1865-Spring 1874, M91.3; 12.0 linear feet
  Correspondence, mostly letters received by Howard (letters sent are contained in letterpress volumes or scribes copy-books, M91.7) dealing with his service as Commissioner of the Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, 1865 to 1874. An incomplete index to these letters and three volumes of abstracts (M91.9) are available for use in Special Collections. Included are semi-official exchanges with Bureau agents, letters concerning the operation of and investigations into the Bureau, as well as correspondence with freedmen and African-American leaders, including southern black Reconstruction era politicians. This series also covers the founding of Howard University and the First Congregational Church in Washington, D.C., and the 1872 peace mission to Cochise and the Chiricahua Apaches
  - 1865 May 01 - 1865 May 16 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1865 May 17 - 1865 May 19 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1865 May 20 - 1865 May 23 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1865 May 24 - 1865 May 31 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1865 Jun 01 - 1865 Jun 07 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1865 Jun 08 - 1865 Jun 14 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1865 Jun 15 - 1865 Jun 19 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1865 Jun 20 - 1865 Jun 23 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1865 Jun 24 - 1865 Jun 30 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1865 Jul 01 - 1865 Jul 05 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1865 Jul 06 - 1865 Jul 08 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1865 Jul 09 - 1865 Jul 10 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1865 Jul 11 - 1865 Jul 14 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 1865 Jul 15 - 1865 Jul 17 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 1865 Jul 18 - 1865 Jul 20 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 1865 Jul 21 - 1865 Jul 23 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 1865 Jul 24 - 1865 Jul 25 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 1865 Jul 26 - 1865 Jul 27 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 1865 Jul 28 - 1865 Jul 31 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 1865 Aug 01 - 1865 Aug 03 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 1865 Aug 04 - 1865 Aug 08 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - 1865 Aug 09 - 1865 Aug 11 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - 1865 Aug 12 - 1865 Aug 18 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - 1865 Aug 19 - 1865 Aug 24 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - 1865 Aug 25 - 1865 Aug 28 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - 1865 Aug 29 - 1865 Aug 30 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - 1865 Sep 01 - 1865 Sep 07 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - 1865 Sep 08 - 1865 Sep 09 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - 1865 Sep 10 - 1865 Sep 13 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - 1865 Sep 14 - 1865 Sep 15 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - 1865 Sep 16 - 1865 Sep 18 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - 1865 Sep 19 - 1865 Sep 20 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - 1865 Sep 21 - 1865 Sep 23 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - 1865 Sep 24 - 1865 Sep 26 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - 1865 Sep 27 - 1865 Sep 28 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - 1865 Sep 29 - 1865 Sep 30 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - 1865 Oct 01 - 1865 Oct 04 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - 1865 Oct 05 - 1865 Oct 11 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - 1865 Oct 12 - 1865 Oct 31 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - 1865 Oct 26 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - 1865 Nov 01 - 1865 Nov 07 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - 1865 Nov 08 - 1865 Nov 20 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - 1865 Nov 21 - 1865 Nov 22 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - 1865 Nov 23 - 1865 Nov 24 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - 1865 Nov 25 - 1865 Nov 28 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - 1865 Nov 29 - 1865 Nov 30 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - 1865 Dec 01 - 1865 Dec 04 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - 1865 Dec 05 - 1865 Dec 10 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - 1865 Dec 11 - 1865 Dec 12 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - 1865 Dec 13 - 1865 Dec 15 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - 1865 Dec 15 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - 1865 Dec 16 - 1865 Dec 18 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - 1865 Dec 19 - 1865 Dec 23 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - 1865 Dec 24 - 1865 Dec 28 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - 1865 Dec 29 - 1865 Dec 31 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - 1866 Jan 01 - 1866 Jan 02 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - 1866 Jan 03 - 1866 Jan 08 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - 1866 Jan 09 - 1866 Jan 12 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - 1866 Jan 13 - 1866 Jan 16 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - 1866 Jan 17 - 1866 Jan 19 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - 1866 Jan 20 - 1866 Jan 23 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - 1866 Jan 24 - 1866 Jan 26 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - 1866 Jan 27 - 1866 Jan 31 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - 1866 Feb 01 - 1866 Feb 04 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - 1866 Feb 08 - 1866 Feb 10 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - 1866 Feb 11 - 1866 Feb 13 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - 1866 Feb 14 - 1866 Feb 19 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - 1866 Feb 20 - 1866 Feb 21 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - 1866 Feb 22 - 1866 Feb 24 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - 1866 Feb 25 - 1866 Feb 27 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - 1866 Feb 28 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - 1866 Mar 01 - 1866 Mar 02 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1866 Mar 03 - 1866 Mar 08 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1866 Mar 09 - 1866 Mar 12 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1866 Mar 13 - 1866 Mar 16 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1866 Mar 17 - 1866 Mar 20 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1866 Mar 21 - 1866 Mar 22 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1866 Mar 23 - 1866 Mar 26 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1866 Mar 27 - 1866 Mar 28 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1866 Mar 29 - 1866 Mar 31 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1866 Apr 01 - 1866 Apr 06 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1866 Apr 07 - 1866 Apr 14 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1866 Apr 15 - 1866 Apr 21 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1866 Apr 22 - 1866 Apr 27 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 1866 Apr 28 - 1866 Apr 30 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 1866 May 01 - 1866 May 06 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 1866 May 07 - 1866 May 13 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 1866 May 14 - 1866 May 18 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 1866 May 19 - 1866 May 23 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 1866 May 24 - 1866 May 28 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 1866 May 29 - 1866 May 31 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 1866 Jun 01 - 1866 Jun 06 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - 1866 Jun 07 - 1866 Jun 08 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - 1866 Jun 09 - 1866 Jun 11 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 1866 Jun 12 - 1866 Jun 14 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - 1866 Jun 15 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - 1866 Jun 16 - 1866 Jun 18 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - 1866 Jun 19 - 1866 Jun 21 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - 1866 Jun 22 - 1866 Jun 25 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - 1866 Jun 26 - 1866 Jun 30 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - 1866 Jul 01 - 1866 Jul 03 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - 1866 Jul 04 - 1866 Jul 06 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - 1866 Jul 07 - 1866 Jul 09 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - 1866 Jul 10 - 1866 Jul 12 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - 1866 Jul 13 - 1866 Jul 16 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - 1866 Jul 17 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - 1866 Jul 18 - 1866 Jul 20 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - 1866 Jul 21 - 1866 Jul 24 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - 1866 Jul 25 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - 1866 Jul 26 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - 1866 Jul 27 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - 1866 Jul 28 - 1866 Jul 29 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - 1866 Jul 30 - 1866 Jul 31 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - 1866 Aug 01 - 1866 Aug 03 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - 1866 Aug 04 - 1866 Aug 06 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - 1866 Aug 07 - 1866 Aug 09 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - 1866 Aug 10 - 1866 Aug 13 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - 1866 Aug 14 - 1866 Aug 15 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - 1866 Aug 16 - 1866 Aug 20 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - 1866 Aug 21 - 1866 Aug 23 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - 1866 Aug 24 - 1866 Aug 26 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - 1866 Aug 27 - 1866 Aug 31 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - 1866 Sep 01 - 1866 Sep 04 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - 1866 Sep 05 - 1866 Sep 07 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - 1866 Sep 08 - 1866 Sep 10 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - 1866 Sep 11 - 1866 Sep 13 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - 1866 Sep 14 - 1866 Sep 16 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - 1866 Sep 17 - 1866 Sep 18 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - 1866 Sep 19 - 1866 Sep 20 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - 1866 Sep 21 - 1866 Sep 23 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - 1866 Sep 24 - 1866 Sep 26 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - 1866 Sep 27 - 1866 Sep 30 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - 1866 Oct 01 - 1866 Oct 03 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - 1866 Oct 04 - 1866 Oct 07 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - 1866 Oct 08 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - 1866 Oct 09 - 1866 Oct 12 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - 1866 Oct 13 - 1866 Oct 15 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - 1866 Oct 16 - 1866 Oct 18 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - 1866 Oct 19 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - 1866 Oct 20 - 1866 Oct 22 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - 1866 Oct 23 - 1866 Oct 25 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - 1866 Oct 26 - 1866 Oct 28 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - 1866 Oct 29 - 1866 Oct 30 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - 1866 Oct 31 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - 1866 Nov 01 - 1866 Nov 03 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - 1866 Nov 04 - 1866 Nov 06 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - 1866 Nov 07 - 1866 Nov 09 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - 1866 Nov 10 - 1866 Nov 11 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - 1866 Nov 12 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - 1866 Nov 13 - 1866 Nov 14 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - 1866 Nov 15 - 1866 Nov 17 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - 1866 Nov 18 - 1866 Nov 20 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - 1866 Nov 21 - 1866 Nov 22 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - 1866 Nov 23 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - 1866 Nov 24 - 1866 Nov 26 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - 1866 Nov 27 - 1866 Nov 29 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1866 Nov 30 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1866 Dec 01 - 1866 Dec 04 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1866 Dec 05 - 1866 Dec 07 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1866 Dec 08 - 1866 Dec 11 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1866 Dec 12 - 1866 Dec 13 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1866 Dec 14 - 1866 Dec 16 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 1866 Dec 17 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1866 Dec 18 - 1866 Dec 19 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 1866 Dec 20 - 1866 Dec 22 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 1866 Dec 23 - 1866 Dec 26 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 1866 Dec 27 - 1866 Dec 31 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 1867 Jan 01 - 1867 Jan 07 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 1867 Jan 08 - 1867 Jan 13 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 1867 Jan 14 - 1867 Jan 19 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 1867 Jan 20 - 1867 Jan 22 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 1867 Jan 23 - 1867 Jan 24 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 1867 Jan 25 - 1867 Jan 28 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 1867 Jan 29 - 1867 Jan 31 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 1867 Feb 01 - 1867 Feb 02 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - 1867 Feb 03 - 1867 Feb 06 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - 1867 Feb 07 - 1867 Feb 09 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 1867 Feb 10 - 1867 Feb 11 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 1867 Feb 12 - 1867 Feb 17 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 1867 Feb 18 - 1867 Feb 24 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 1867 Feb 25 - 1867 Feb 28 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - 1867 Mar 01 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - 1867 Mar 02 - 1867 Mar 04 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - 1867 Mar 05 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - 1867 Mar 06 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - 1867 Mar 07 - 1867 Mar 08 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - 1867 Mar 09 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - 1867 Mar 10 - 1867 Mar 11 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - 1867 Mar 12 - 1867 Mar 13 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - 1867 Mar 14 - 1867 Mar 15 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - 1867 Mar 16 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - 1867 Mar 17 - 1867 Mar 19 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - 1867 Mar 20 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - 1867 Mar 21 - 1867 Mar 24 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - 1867 Mar 25 - 1867 Mar 26 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - 1867 Mar 27 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - 1867 Mar 28 - 1867 Mar 31 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - 1867 Apr 01 - 1867 Apr 03 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - 1867 Apr 04 - 1867 Apr 06 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - 1867 Apr 07 - 1867 Apr 08 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - 1867 Apr 09 - 1867 Apr 10 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - 1867 Apr 11 - 1867 Apr 12 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - 1867 Apr 13 - 1867 Apr 14 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - 1867 Apr 15 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - 1867 Apr 16 - 1867 Apr 17 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - 1867 Apr 18 - 1867 Apr 19 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - 1867 Apr 20 - 1867 Apr 22 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - 1867 Apr 23 - 1867 Apr 26 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - 1867 Apr 27 - 1867 Apr 30 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - 1867 May 01 - 1867 May 06 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - 1867 May 07 - 1867 May 08 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - 1867 May 09 - 1867 May 10 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - 1867 May 11 - 1867 May 12 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - 1867 May 13 - 1867 May 15 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - 1867 May 16 - 1867 May 17 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - 1867 May 18 - 1867 May 20 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - 1867 May 21 - 1867 May 22 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - 1867 May 23 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - 1867 May 24 - 1867 May 26 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - 1867 May 27 - 1867 May 28 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - 1867 May 29 - 1867 May 31 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - 1867 Jun 01 - 1867 Jun 03 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - 1867 Jun 04 - 1867 Jun 07 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - 1867 Jun 08 - 1867 Jun 11 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - 1867 Jun 12 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - 1867 Jun 13 - 1867 Jun 14 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - 1867 Jun 15 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - 1867 Jun 16 - 1867 Jun 17 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - 1867 Jun 18 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - 1867 Jun 19 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - 1867 Jun 20 - 1867 Jun 23 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - 1867 Jun 24 - 1867 Jun 26 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - 1867 Jun 27 - 1867 Jun 30 (Box 5, Folder 78)